本字幕由YYeTs人人影视修正制作
最新最快的HR-HDTV 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
后期：鱼子酱
今天有人问我...
Somebody asked me today...
"菲尔  随便让你选个地方  你会想到哪去?"
"Phil, if you could be anywhere, where would you like to be?"
我跟他说  "大概就是这里"
I said to him, "Probably right here."
这里是内华达州的艾科  今天国内最高气温华氏79度
Elko, Nevada. Our nation's high at 79 today.
加州明天会有温暖的天气...
In California, they'll have warm weather tomorrow...
帮派斗殴和超贵的房地产
gang wars and some very overpriced real estate.
太平洋岸西北部会有很高大的树
Up in the Pacific Northwest, they'll have some very tall trees.
落矶山脉天气晴朗
It will be clear across the Rockies and the Great Plains.
不过要小心  有麻烦要来了
But look out, here comes trouble.
天啊!  直接对着我们而来  小心
Oh, boy! Front coming our way. Look out.
那对三河地区会有什么影响?
What will that mean to us in the Three Rivers area?
这一大片蓝色区块!  是寒冷的北极气团
One of these big blue things! This cold, frigid, Arctic air.
从北方来的大片云团
This big mass out of the north.
它会和来自墨西哥湾的湿热空气相遇...
It will meet up with all this moisture coming out of the Gulf...
在高海拔地区混合  然后会导致降雪
mix together at high altitudes and cause some snow.
它不会侵袭匹兹堡  而会抵达亚图纳
It won't hit us here in Pittsburgh. It will push off and hit Altoona.
好险
Close call.
让我们来看未来五天的天气预测
Let's take a look at the five- day.
没什么好担心的
Nothing to be too scared about.
穿得暖和一点  可是不必穿雨靴
Bundle up warm, but leave your galoshes at home.
十点钟我不会在这里
I won't be here for the 10:00.
明天是土拨鼠节  我要去普苏塔尼...
Tomorrow is Groundhog Day, and I'm going out to Punxsutawney...
参加全国历史最久的土拨鼠节庆
for our country's oldest groundhog festival.
根据传说  明天2月2日...
According to the legend, tomorrow, February 2...
如果土拨鼠看到自己的影子  冬天就还有6周
if the groundhog sees his shadow, we'll have six more weeks of winter.
-祈求好运吧  -好像很好玩的样子
- Keep your fingers crossed. - Sounds like a lot of fun.
这是你连续第3年去吧?
This is your third year in a row isn't it?
第4年
Four, Nan.
谢谢你  菲尔
Thanks, Phil.
接下来  黛安·金曼要探讨电影中的性与暴力
Up next: Diane Kingman looks at sex and violence in the movies.
不要走开
Stay with us.
-好了  -到普苏塔尼玩得愉快
- We're clear. - Have fun in Punxsutawney.
告诉你  美发妹
For your information, Hairdo...
有家无线电视台对我有兴趣
there is a major network interested in me.
一定是购物频道
That would be the Home Shopping Network.
谢了  赖瑞  到车上等
Thanks, Larry. Go wait in the van.
说得真妙  "高大的树"
That was nice. "Big trees."
闭嘴  亨利  你能不能报十点的气象?
Stop, Henny. Can you handle the 10:00 or not?
如果你不想太赶的话  我可以报明天5点那节
If you don't want to rush back, I can do the 5:00 tomorrow.
我会在普苏塔尼多待一秒钟?  别闹了!
I want to stay an extra second in Punxsutawney? Please!
丽塔觉得留在那边参加别的活动很不错...
Rita thinks it would be great to stay for some of the other events...
可以拍一些很棒的镜头
get some incredible footage.
群众  欢乐  还有刺激
The people and the fun, the excitement.
你还没跟她共事过  她人很好
You haven't worked with her yet. She's really nice.
她是很好的制作人
She's gonna be a really good producer.
你们会很开心的
You guys will have fun.
她的开心和我的不一样  我5点会来  丽塔
She's fun, but not my kind of fun. I will be here for the 5:00. Rita.
可以帮我保密吗  赖瑞?
Can you keep a secret, Larry?
我可能会离开PBH
I'm probably leaving PBH.
这是我们最后一次一起报导土拨鼠节
So this will be the last time we do the Groundhog together.
土拨鼠节有什么不好?
What's wrong with the Groundhog Festival?
我在圣地牙哥报导燕子返回卡皮卓诺6年
In San Diego, I covered the swallows returning to Capistrano six years.
总有一天会有人看到我在访问土拨鼠
Someday somebody will see me interviewing a groundhog...
我根本没有前途
and think I don't have a future.
那会是很好的报导
I think it's a nice story.
它爬出来  四处看看
He comes out, and he looks around.
皱起小鼻子  到底有没有看到影子呢
He wrinkles up his little nose. He sees his shadow or he doesn't see it.
很棒  观众会喜欢
It's nice. People like it.
你是新来的吧?
You are new, aren't you?
观众也喜欢血香肠
People like blood sausage too.
观众是白痴
People are morons.
你的态度还真不错
Nice attitude.
照照镜子  看你报导土拨鼠节是什么德性
Look in the mirror and see what you look like doing that groundhog thing.
做一次给我看?
For me? Once?
它爬出来  看到自己的影子
He comes out and looks at his little shadow.
-要来点血香肠吗?  -我喜欢血香肠
- Would you like some blood sausage? - I like blood sausage.
往119号公路  普苏塔尼
欢迎来到普苏塔尼
世界气象首都  始于1887年
WPBH第9台  行动新闻
丽塔  我不能住在这里
Rita, I can't stay here.
-真难搞  -我来处理  怎么回事?
- Prima donna. - I'll handle it. What's the matter?
我讨厌这地方  两年前我就来过  当时好惨
I hate this place. I stayed here two years ago. I was miserable.
-这根本是狗窝  我不要住在这里  -你不用住在这里
- It's a fleabag. I'm not staying here. - You're not staying here.
不用吗?
I'm not?
赖瑞只是让我下车  我帮你订了很棒的旅馆
Larry's dropping me off. I booked you in a nice bed- and- breakfast.
很好  这是优秀制作人必备的特点
Great. I think this is the trait of a really good producer:
让明星开心
Keep the talent happy.
我很乐意效劳
Anything I can do.
愿意服侍我上厕所吗?
Would you help me with my pelvic tilt?
别得寸进尺
Within reason.
你要和我跟赖瑞吃晚餐吗?
Would you like to have dinner with Larry and me?
不  谢谢  我看过赖瑞吃饭的德性
No, thank you. I've seen Larry eat.
去睡觉吧  明天早上见
Get your sleep. I'll see you in the morning.
别迟到
Don't be late.
他真的自称为"明星"吗?
Did he actually call himself"the talent"?
该起床了
Okay, campers, rise and shine.
别忘了你的装备  今天外面很冷
Don't forget your booties because it's cold out there today.
外面每天都很冷  难道这里是迈阿密海滩吗?
It's cold out there every day. What is this, Miami Beach?
不可能  等一下你就可以在大风雪中冒险了
Not hardly. You can expect hazardous travel later with that blizzard thing.
"大风雪"?  接下来是气象报告
"That blizzard thing"? Here's the report.
气象局说会有大风雪
The National Weather Service is calling for a big blizzard thing.
对  不过今天特别刺激还有一个原因
They are. But there's another reason why today is especially exciting.
天气特别冷
Especially cold.
每个人唇边都冒出一个大问题...
The big question on everybody's lips...
龟裂的嘴唇
On their chapped lips.
你想菲尔出来会看到影子吗?
Do you think Phil will come out and see his shadow?
-普苏塔尼菲尔  -没错  土拨鼠投手
- Punxsutawney Phil. - That's right, woodchuck chuckers.
今天是土拨鼠节!
It's Groundhog Day!
-起来看土拨鼠吧!  -过来  土拨鼠
- Get up and check that hog! - Come here, groundhog!
早安
Good morning.
-你会去看土拨鼠吗?  -会
- You off to see the groundhog? - I am.
今年会是早春吗?
Do you think it will be an early spring?
我预测是3月21日
I'm predicting March 21.
猜得好
Good guess.
我想那会是春天的第一天
I think that actually is the first day of spring.
睡得好吗  康纳先生?
Did you sleep well, Mr. Connors?
我一个人睡  蓝太太
I slept alone, Mrs. Lancaster.
-想喝咖啡吗?  -今天早上...
- Would you like some coffee? - Is there any possibility...
有没有浓缩咖啡或卡布奇诺?
of getting an espresso or a cappuccino this morning?
我真的不知道
I really don't know.
"浓缩咖啡"或"卡布奇诺"怎么拼?
How to spell "espresso" or "cappuccino" ?
这就可以了
This looks fine.
-祝你这次玩得愉快  -一定会的
- I hope you enjoy the festivities. - I'm sure I will.
听说有大风雪
There's talk of a blizzard.
天气会有变化  大风雪会被吹走
We may catch a break and have that blizzard blow by us.
这股从南方来的湿热空气...
All this moisture coming up out of the south...
可能会吹到我们的东边
will probably push on east of us.
它会在高海拔地区结晶  并为我们带来降雪
At high altitudes it will crystallize and give us what we call snow.
可能会有积雪...
Probably will be some accumulation...
不过今天普苏塔尼最高温会达到30度  晚上则有十几度...
but here in Punxsutawney our high will be about 30 today, teens tonight.
今明两天气温骤降的机率大约20%
Chance of precipitation about 20 percent today and tomorrow.
你是想谈天气还是在闲聊?
Did you want to talk about the weather or were you just making chitchat?
-闲聊  -回头见
- Chitchat. - See you later.
-再见  -你今天会退房吗?
- Bye. - Will you be checking out today?
今天离开的机率是100%
Chance of departure today: 100 percent.
菲尔·康纳?  我就知道是你!
Phil Connors? I thought that was you!
你好吗?  谢谢观赏
How you doing? Thanks for watching.
别说你不记得我  我可是记得很清楚喔
Don't tell me you don't remember me. I sure as heck- fire remember you.
-想不起来  -尼德·莱尔森
- Not a chance. - Ned Ryerson!
尖鼻子尼德  秃头尼德
Needlenose Ned. Ned the Head.
少来了  老兄  西凯高中
Come on, buddy. Case Western High.
我表演过肚脐吹口哨  乒!
I did the whistling belly button trick at the high school talent show. Bing!
高三得了严重的带状疱疹  差点毕不了业
Got the shingles real bad senior year, almost didn't graduate.
乒!
Bing again!
我跟你妹玛莉约会过  直到你阻止我为止
I dated your sister Mary Pat till you told me not to anymore.
尼德·莱尔森?
Ned Ryerson?
你后来跑去表演职业肚皮秀了吗?
Did you turn pro with that belly button thing or what?
-我在拉保险  -令人震惊
- I sell insurance. - What a shock.
你有保寿险吗?  随时都能再多买一份喔
Do you have life insurance? You could always use a little more.
对不对?  对不对?
Am I right or am I right or am I right? Right?
我很想站在这里跟你聊  可是我不行
I would love to stand here and talk with you, but I'm not going to.
-再见  -我陪你走
- See you. - I'll walk with you.
我只要遇到机会  就会像牛一样紧追不放
Whenever I see an opportunity now, I charge it like a bull.
我现在是猛牛尼德
Ned the Bull, that's me now.
我有朋友靠保险金发财
I have friends who live and die by the actuarial tables.
实在很走运
It's all one big crap shoot.
你听过一次缴终身保险吗?
Have you ever heard of single premium life?
非常适合你
I think that really could be the ticket for you.
天啊!  见到你真高兴!
God! It is so good to see you!
-你晚餐时间有什么计划?  -我有事
- What are you doing for dinner? - Something else.
见到你真好  尖头  保重
It's been great seeing you, Needlehead. Take care.
小心那一步  很重要!
Watch out for that first step. It's a doozy!
火鸡丘
奏起音乐  乐队刚开始演奏
Strike up the music The band has begun
宾州波尔卡舞曲
The Pennsylvania Polka
邀请你的伙伴一起来玩
Pick out your partner and join in the fun
它起源自史坎顿  现在已是第一名
It started in Scranton It's now number one
会让人开心无比
It's gonna entertain you
菲尔  在这边
Phil, over here!
你到哪去了?
Where have you been?
好可怕  我被一条大水蛭缠上
It was horrible. A giant leech got me.
你错过了很好玩的东西  这些人太棒了
You're missing all the fun. These people are great.
有人彻夜狂欢  一直唱到冷得受不了
Some have been partying all night. They sing until they get too cold...
然后就坐在火堆旁取暖  又继续唱歌
then they sit by the fire, get warm and sing some more.
他们是乡下人  丽塔
They're hicks, Rita.
没有我你睡得还好吗?  是不是辗转难眠?
Did you sleep okay without me? You tossed and turned, didn't you?
-你太离谱了  -谁说的?
- You're incredible. - Who told you?
土拨鼠时间到了
It's groundhog time.
倒数  三...
On me in three.
二  一
Two, one.
每年此时  全国的焦点都集中在这宾州小镇上...
Once a year, the eyes of the nation turn to this tiny Pennsylvania hamlet...
想看一名大师工作的情形
to watch a master at work.
这位大师?  普苏塔尼的菲尔...
The master? Punxsutawney Phil...
全球最著名的气象预报员...
the world's most famous weatherman, the groundhog...
它是一只土拨鼠  传说它能预言早春的降临
who, as legend has it, can predict the coming of an early spring.
今天我们要自问的问题是  "菲尔觉得运气如何?"
The question we have to ask ourselves today is, "Does Phil feel lucky?"
然后又是同样的老把戏
Then it's the same old schtick.
拿着大棍子的家伙敲门
The guy with the big stick raps on the door.
把那只老鼠抱出来  跟它说话
They pull the little rat out. They talk to him.
老鼠回答他  然后他们就说会发生什么事
The rat talks back and then they tell us what's gonna happen.
它很可爱吧?
Isn't he cute?
你喜欢男友有暴牙吗?
You like your guys with prominent upper teeth?
不喜欢
No.
现在是2月2日7点20分30秒...
"This February 2, at 7:20 and 30 seconds...
普苏塔尼的菲尔  先知中的先知...
Punxsutawney Phil, the seer of seers...
预言家中的预言家...
prognosticator of prognosticators...
很不情愿地出现在...
emerged reluctantly, but alertly...
宾州的普苏塔尼...
in Punxsutawney, Pennsylvania...
它用土拨鼠语说...
and stated in Groundhogese...
"我看到了影子"
I definitely see a shadow."
抱歉  各位  冬天还有6周
Sorry, folks. Six more weeks of winter.
倒数三  二  一
On me in three. Two, one.
电视没办法捕捉到一只大松鼠...
Television really fails to capture the true excitement...
预测天气的真实兴奋感
of a large squirrel predicting the weather.
我很感激能到这里来
I, for one, am very grateful to have been here.
菲尔康纳在普苏塔尼的报导  再会
From Punxsutawney, this is Phil Connors. So long.
想用不嘲讽的方式再试一次吗?
Want to try it again without the sarcasm?
拍完了  我要走了
We got it. I'm out of here.
真难搞
Prima donnas.
你们看看
Boy, take a look at this.
-怎么回事?  -我不知道
- What is going on? - I don't know.
也许是我们不该遇到的大风雪
Perhaps it's that giant blizzard we're not supposed to get.
不可能
This is impossible.
只有我才能按喇叭
Nobody honks this horn but me, pal.
把车子拖走
Take this rig out of here.
警官  怎么回事?
Commander, what's going on?
没事  要封闭路面
There's nothing going on. We're closing the road.
-大风雪逼近了  -什么风雪?  只是雪花而已
- Big blizzard moving in. - What blizzard? It's a couple flakes.
你没听气象预报吗?  这里有大风暴
Don't you listen to the weather? We got a major storm here.
我是报气象的!
I make the weather!
从墨西哥湾来的湿热空气...
All this moisture coming up out of the Gulf...
会往东移侵袭亚图纳
will push off to the east and hit Altoona.
老兄  你头上有雪
Pal, you got that moisture on your head.
不回普苏塔尼就会冻死在这里
You can go back to Punxsutawney or you can freeze to death.
看你的选择  怎么样?
It's your choice. What's it gonna be?
我在想
I'm thinking.
所有长途线路都不通?
All the long- distance lines are down?
卫星呢?  太空中也下雪吗?
What about the satellite? Is it snowing in space?
难道没有线路开放供紧急状况或名人使用吗?
Don't you have a line you keep open for emergencies or for celebrities?
我两者都是  我是发生紧急状况的名人
I'm both. I'm a celebrity in an emergency.
帮我接通好吗?
Can you patch me through on that line, please?
可以再来杯酒吗?
Can I have one more with booze in it?
我好喜欢这里
I like it here.
菲尔  你会参加土拨鼠晚餐吗?
Phil, are you going to the groundhog dinner?
我午餐吃了土拨鼠  味道还不错
I had groundhog for lunch. It wasn't bad.
满像鸡肉的  你们去吧
Tastes like chicken. You two run along.
今晚很帅喔
Looking foxy tonight, man.
你的童子军今年会再卖饼干吗?
Is your troop selling cookies again this year?
真好笑  菲尔
That's so funny, Phil.
你要做什么?
What are you gonna do?
回房间洗个热水澡
I'm going back to my room and take a hot shower.
说不定看看好色客杂志
Maybe read Hustler or something.
随便你
Suit yourself.
天啊!
God!
老妈  没有热水吗?
Yo, Mom. Isn't there any hot water?
今天没有
There wouldn't be today.
当然没有  我真笨
Of course not. Silly me.
祝你好梦
Sweet dreams.
该起床了
Okay, campers, rise and shine.
别忘了你的装备  今天外面很冷
Don't forget your booties because it's cold out there today.
外面每天都很冷  难道这里是迈...
It's cold out there every day. What is this, Mia...
干得好  小子  你们播的是昨天的带子
Nice going, boys. You're playing yesterday's tape.
等一下你就可以在大风雪中冒险了
You can expect hazardous travel later with that blizzard thing.
"大风雪"?  接下来是气象报告
"That blizzard thing"? Here's the report.
气象局说会有大风雪
The National Weather Service is calling for a big blizzard thing.
对  不过今天特别刺激还有一个原因
They are. But there's another reason why today is especially exciting.
天气特别冷
Especially cold.
每个人唇边都冒出一个大问题...
The big question on everybody's lips...
龟裂的嘴唇
Chapped lips.
你想菲尔出来会看到影子吗?
Do you think Phil will come out and see his shadow?
-普苏塔尼菲尔  -没错  土拨鼠投手
- Punxsutawney Phil. - That's right, woodchuck chuckers.
今天是土拨鼠节!
It's Groundhog Day!
-起来看土拨鼠吧!  -过来  土拨鼠
- Get up and check that hog! - Come here, groundhog!
怎么搞的?
What the hell?
早安  要去看土拨鼠吗?
Good morning. Off to see the groundhog?
今年会是早春吗?
Think it will be an early spring?
我们昨天谈过了吧?
Didn't we do this yesterday?
我听不懂你的意思
I don't know what you mean.
别耍我  肥猪
Don't mess with me, Pork Chop.
-今天几号?  -2月2日土拨鼠节
- What day is this? - It's February 2. Groundhog Day.
我以为是昨天
I thought it was yesterday.
睡得好吗  康纳先生?
Did you sleep well, Mr. Connors?
睡得好吗?
Did I sleep well?
-想喝点咖啡吗?  -好  我要双份的
- Would you like some coffee? - Please. I think I'll have a double.
祝你玩得开心
I hope you enjoy the festivities.
听说有大风雪
There's talk of a blizzard.
你有"似曾相识"的感觉吗?
Do you ever have deja vu?
应该没有  但我可以问厨房
I don't think so, but I could check with the kitchen.
没关系  谢谢
That's okay. Thank you.
你今天要退房吗?
Will you be checking out today?
我离开的机率是80%
I'd say the chance of departure is 80 percent.
75  80
Seventy- five, eighty.
对不起
Excuse me.
大家要去哪?
Where is everybody going?
去火鸡丘  今天是土拨鼠节
To Gobbler's Knob. It's Groundhog Day.
那还是一年一次吧?
It's still just once a year, isn't it?
菲尔·康纳  我就知道是你
Phil Connors. I thought that was you.
别说你不记得我  我可是记得很清楚喔
Don't you say you don't remember me. I sure as heck- fire remember you.
尼德·莱尔森?
Ned Ryerson?
乒!  一猜就中!
Bing! First shot right out of the box!
你好吗  老兄?
How's it going, old buddy?
我不太舒服  失陪了
Actually, I'm not feeling well. Would you excuse me?
真好玩  你竟然提到你的健康
It's funny you should mention your health.
你绝对猜不到我做哪一行
You will never guess what I do now.
-拉保险吗?  -又猜中了
- Do you sell insurance? - Bing again!
你今天真是聪明
You are sharp as a tack today.
你有寿险吗?  如果有  还可以多买一点
Do you have life insurance? If you do, you could always use more.
对吧?  谁不是呢?
Right? Who couldn't?
我感觉得到你没有保险
You know something? I got a feeling you ain't got any.
-对不对?  -我要走了
- Am I right or am I right? - I gotta go.
小心那一步  很重要
Watch out for that first step. It's a doozy.
菲尔  在这边!
Phil, over here!
-你到哪去了?  -丽塔  帮我一个忙
- Where have you been? - Rita, do me a favor.
我需要有人好好赏我一巴掌
I need someone to give me a good hard slap in the face.
-怎么样?  -很好
- How's that? - Good.
右脸也需要的话通知我  随时奉陪
If you need help with the other cheek, let me know. I'm right here.
-不太对劲  -你是醉了还是怎样?
- Something's going on. - Are you drunk or something?
喝醉有趣多了  我能严肃一分钟吗?
Drunk's more fun. Can I be serious for a minute?
-我不知道  你能吗?  -我现在很严肃
- I don't know. Can you? - I'm being serious.
我有问题了  可能有问题了
I'm having a problem. I may be having a problem.
-土拨鼠时间到了  -我就知道你会那么说
- It's groundhog time. - I knew you would say that.
我真的觉得很奇怪
I really feel weird.
我们先拍完再谈
Let's just do this, then we'll talk.
倒数三...
On me in three.
二  一
Two, one.
土拨鼠节又到了
It's Groundhog Day again.
我们一定会在火鸡丘等待...
That must mean we're at Gobbler's Knob waiting for the forecast...
全球最著名的土拨鼠预报员...
from the world's most famous groundhog weatherman...
普苏塔尼菲尔...
Punxsutawney Phil...
它将告诉我们冬天还有多久
who's just about to tell us how much more winter we can expect.
好热闹哦
This is a riot.
它很可爱吧?
Isn't he cute?
现在是2月2日7点20分30秒...
"This February 2, at 7:20 and 30 seconds...
普苏塔尼的菲尔  先知中的先知...
Punxsutawney Phil, the seer of seers...
预言家中的预言家...
prognosticator of prognosticators...
很不情愿地出现在宾州的...
emerged reluctantly, but alertly in Punxsut...
对  老兄  我知道有大风雪
Yeah, Sport, I know there's a blizzard.
长途线路什么时候修好?
When are the long- distance lines gonna be repaired?
万一没有明天呢?  今天就没有啊
What if there is no tomorrow? There wasn't one today.
喂?
Hello?
早安  要去看土拨鼠吗?
Good morning. Off to see the groundhog?
睡得好吗  康...
Did you sleep well, Mr...
我就知道...
I thought...
别说你不记得我  我可是记得很清楚喔
Don't say you don't remember me. I sure as heck- fire remember you.
是我  尼德·莱尔森!
It's me, Ned Ryerson!
尖鼻子尼德  秃头尼德  老兄  西凯...
Needlenose Ned. Ned the Head. Come on, buddy. Case Western...
这边!
Over here!
-你到哪去了?  -谈点工作以外的事好吗?
- Where have you been? - Can we talk about a nonwork matter?
-你从来不谈工作  -我们真的需要谈谈  来
- You never talk about work. - We really have to talk. Come on.
-这是创意会议  别想跟来  -等等  我们有工作要做
- It's a creative meeting. Forget it. - Wait a second. We've got work to do.
我没有  我已经做2次了
I don't. I've already done it twice.
等你拍完  跟我在餐厅碰面
When you get finished, meet me in the diner.
-怎么回事?  -不知道
- What's that all about? - I don't know.
真难搞
Prima donnas.
还要咖啡吗?
More coffee, hon?
不  谢了  买单
No, thanks. Just the check, please.
-甜点真可口  -那当然
- These sticky buns are heaven. - Aren't they?
随便放
Just put that anywhere, pal.
救得好
Good save.
你怎会病到不能工作  理由最好漂亮一点
Tell me why you're too sick to work, and it better be good.
我不断重覆经历同一天
I'm reliving the same day over and over.
土拨鼠节  今天
Groundhog Day. Today.
我在等你的笑点
I'm waiting for the punch line.
真的  这是第三次了
Really. This is the third time.
就像昨天根本没发生过
It's like yesterday never happened.
我一直搞不懂  你干嘛编这套故事
I am racking my brain, but I can't imagine why you'd make this up.
我没有编  我在求你帮忙
I'm not making it up. I am asking you for help!
你要我怎么做?
What do you want me to do?
我不知道  你是制作人  想想办法
I don't know! You're a producer, come up with something.
想听我的建议吗?
You want my advice?
要我相信你的说法的话最好去检查你的脑袋
You should get your head examined if you expect me to believe that story.
你和土拨鼠菲尔同名?
Like the groundhog Phil?
找找你的影子  老兄
Look out for your shadow, pal.
白痴  你的公车要走了
Morons, your bus is leaving.
好了吗?  我们最好赶快离开...
You guys ready? We better get going...
-在天气变坏之前  -我们回匹兹堡再谈
- to stay ahead of the weather. - Let's talk back in Pittsburgh.
我才不要回匹兹堡
I'm not going back to Pittsburgh.
-为什么?  -因为有大风雪
- Why not? - Because of the blizzard.
你说它会侵袭亚图纳
You said that would hit Altoona.
我知道我是那么说
I know that's what I said.
我想你需要帮忙
I think you need help.
我也一直说我需要帮忙
That's what I've been saying. I need help.
没有斑点  血块
No spots, no clots...
没有肿瘤  机能障碍
no tumors, no lesions...
没有动脉瘤
no aneurisms.
我看没什么问题
None that I can see.
想做断层扫瞄或磁共振成像就得回匹兹堡
If you want a CAT scan or an MRI, you have to go into Pittsburgh.
我没办法回匹兹堡
I can't go into Pittsburgh.
-为什么?  -有大风雪
- Why can't you go into Pittsburgh? - There's a blizzard.
对  大风雪
Right. The blizzard.
知道你需要什么吗  康纳先生?
You know what you may need, Mr. Connors?
切片检查
A biopsy.
精神科医生
A psychiatrist.
这是个很不寻常的问题  康纳先生
That's an unusual problem, Mr. Connors.
我的病人大多是夫妻  一家人
Most of my work is with couples, families.
现在有一个酒鬼
I have an alcoholic now.
你上过大学吧?  该不会是念兽医心理学吧?
You went to college, right? It wasn't veterinary psychology, was it?
你有没有修过跟这有关的课?
Didn't you take some course that covered this stuff?
应该算有吧
Sort of. I guess.
变态心理学
Abnormal psychology.
我该怎么办?
So, what do I do?
你应该再来
I think we should meet again.
明天可以吗?
How's tomorrow for you?
不好吗?
Is that not good?
我有一次去维京群岛
I was in the Virgin Islands once.
遇到一个女孩子
I met a girl.
我们一起吃龙虾  喝鸡尾酒
We ate lobster, drank pina coladas.
黄昏时我们像海獭一样做爱
At sunset, we made love like sea otters.
那真是美好的一天
That was a pretty good day.
我为何不能反覆过那一天?
Why couldn't I get that day over and over and over?
有些人看到这个玻璃杯子...
You know, some guys would look at this glass...
他们会说  "这杯子半空"
and they would say, "That glass is half empty."
其他人会说  "这杯子半满"
Other guys would say, "That glass is half full."
我认为你是"半空"型的人  对不对?
I peg you as a "glass is half empty" kind of guy. Am I right?
如果你困在一个地方每天都完全一样...
What would you do if you were stuck in one place...
做什么都改变不了状况  你会怎么办?
and every day was exactly the same, and nothing that you did mattered?
我的人生就是那样
That sums it up for me.
祝你好运  我半路让你下车
Good luck. I'll drop you off.
-卡住了  要摇一下  -起来
- This thing sticks. You gotta jiggle it. - Come on up here.
-天啊  -钥匙给我
- My gosh. - Give me your keys, pal.
是朋友就不会让你开车  站好  深呼吸
Friends don't let friends drive. Stand up here. Take a deep breath.
你还好吗?  真的?
You feel okay? Really?
你没事了
You're all right.
想在这里还是车上吐?
You want to throw up here or in the car?
-都要  -来吧
- I think both. - Come on.
我不该开车
I don't think I should be driving.
我想也是  小心头
I don't either. Watch your head.
小心膝盖  别受伤了
Watch your knees. Don't break anything.
好  别忘了系安全带
All right. Let's not forget seat belts.
还有谁能去买煎饼?
Who else could go for some flapjacks right now?
拱石州  宾夕法尼亚
我问你们一个问题
Let me ask you guys a question.
-说吧  -万一没有明天呢?
- Shoot. - What if there were no tomorrow?
没有明天?  也就是没有结果啰
No tomorrow? That would mean there would be no consequences.
不会有宿醉  我们可以随心所欲!
There would be no hangovers. We could do whatever we wanted!
没错  想做什么就做什么
That's true. We could do whatever we want.
要是想撞烂邮筒  就让雷夫开车了
If we wanted to hit mailboxes, we could let Ralph drive!
-我想他们要你停车  -抓好
- I think they want you to stop. - Hang on.
人生就是这么一回事
It's the same thing your whole life:
"清理房间"  "站好"  "脚抬起来"
"Clean up your room." " Stand up straight." " Pick up your feet."
"像个男人有担当"  "对你妹好一点"
"Take it like a man." "Be nice to your sister."
"别把啤酒和葡萄酒混合"
"Don't mix beer and wine, ever."
"别在铁轨上开车"
"Don't drive on the railroad tracks."
菲尔  这点我刚好同意
Phil, that's one I happen to agree with.
我不知道  贾斯
I don't know, Gus.
我想有时候就该孤注一掷
Sometimes I think you just have to take the big chances.
我们是警察!  立刻停车!
This is the police! Pull over immediately!
我们在说话
We're talking in here.
我猜他会先转弯
I'm betting he'll swerve first.
我不要再照别人的规则生活了
I'm not gonna live by their rules anymore.
-我注意到了  -做了选择就要接受
- I noticed that. - You make choices and live with them.
我的膝盖
My knee.
让我来应付
Let me handle this.
三个吉士汉堡  两份大薯条...
Three cheeseburgers, two large fries...
两杯巧克力奶昔还有一杯大可乐
two chocolate shakes and one large Coke.
-还有煎饼  -吃煎饼太早了吗?
- And some flapjacks. - Too early for flapjacks?
快起床!
Rise and shine, campers!
别忘了装备  今天外面很冷
Don't forget your booties because it's cold out there today!
外面每天都很冷  这里是迈阿密海滩吗?  不可能
It's cold out there every day. What is this, Miami Beach? Not hardly.
睡得像婴儿一样  谢谢
Slept like a baby. Thank you.
-我想来点咖啡  -你想...
- I'd love some of your coffee. - I hope...
晚一点会下雪  不过大风雪会侵袭城外
Flurries moving in later, but the blizzard will hit outside of town.
蓝太太  今天早上有人找我吗?
Mrs. Lancaster, was anybody looking for me here this morning?
也许是州警?  蓝帽子  佩枪  还有警棍?
Perhaps a state official? Maybe a blue hat, gun, nightstick?
没有那种人  会有吗?
No one like that. Will there be?
显然没有
Apparently not.
请帮我保留房间  我要多待一天
Hold my room for me, please. I'm staying an extra day.
明天见  老爹
Catch you tomorrow, Pops.
菲尔?  菲尔·康纳!
Phil? Phil Connors!
尼德?
Ned?
我喜欢看中年人做事不顾后果
I like to see a man of advancing years throwing caution to the wind.
满激励人心的
It's inspiring, in a way.
我的年纪没你想的那么老
My years are not advancing as fast as you might think.
还要咖啡吗?
More coffee, hon?
拿过来
Just keep it coming, please.
好
Sure thing.
随便放
Just put that anywhere, pal.
救得好
Good save.
你不担心胆固醇  肺癌吗?
Don't you worry about cholesterol, lung cancer, love handles?
我什么都不担心了
I don't worry about anything anymore.
你怎么会这么特别?  大家总有事会担心
What makes you so special? Everybody worries about something.
所以我才特别  我甚至不用牙线剔牙
That's exactly what makes me so special. I don't even have to floss.
怎样?
What?
"可怜的人只会注意自己..."
"The wretch, concentered all in self...
"生活  会丧失名声..."
Living, shall forfeit fair renown...
"而双重的死亡  将从他出现的地方..."
And, doubly dying, shall go down...
"坠落到污秽的尘埃中..."
To the vile dust, from whence he sprung...
"无人哀悼  尊崇  歌颂"
Unwept, unhonor'd, and unsung."
华特·史考特爵士写的
Sir Walter Scott.
-你不喜欢诗?  -我很爱诗
- You don't like poetry? - I love poetry.
我以为是威勒·史考特  我都搞糊涂了
I just thought that was Willard Scott. I was confused.
你想我会这样是因为太自我中心吗?
Do you think I'm acting like this because I'm egocentric?
我知道你很自我中心  那是你的特点
I know you're egocentric. It's your defining characteristic.
你们好了没?  趁天气没变坏前赶快出发
Are you guys ready? We better get going to stay ahead of the weather.
谢了  赖瑞  需要打包吗?
Thanks, Larry. Would you like a doggie bag?
-我留在这里吃完  -我以为你不喜欢这里
- I'll stay here and finish. - I thought you hated this town.
我越来越喜欢了
It's beginning to grow on me.
赖瑞  别看了
Larry, quit staring.
这个很好吃
These are excellent.
今天早上有看到土拨鼠吗?
Did you see the groundhog this morning?
我从不错过
I never miss it.
你贵姓大名?
What's your name?
南茜·泰勒  你是?
Nancy Taylor. And you are?
-你上哪所高中?  -什么?
- What high school did you go to? - What?
-高中  -林肯高中  在匹兹堡
- High school. - Lincoln, in Pittsburgh.
-你是谁?  -你高三的英文老师是谁?
- Who are you? - Who was your senior English teacher?
你在开玩笑吗?
Are you kidding?
-你高三的英文老师是...  -华许老师
- Your 12th- grade English teacher was... - Mrs. Walsh.
南茜  林肯  华许  谢谢
Nancy. Lincoln. Walsh. Thanks very much.
南茜!
Nancy!
林肯高中
Lincoln High School.
华许老师的课我坐你隔壁
I sat next to you in Mrs. Walsh's English class.
对不起
I'm sorry.
-好巧  -你不记得我了吧?
- That's amazing. - You don't remember me, do you?
我还邀请你参加毕业舞会
I even asked you to the prom.
当时我很矮  后来长高了
I was short, and I've sprouted.
天啊!  你好吗?
Gosh! How are you?
很好  你看起来美极了
Great. You look terrific.
简直美呆了
You look very terrific.
-我得做这项报导  -你是记者?
- I have to do this report. - Are you a reporter?
我是匹兹堡第9频道的气象播报员
I'm a weatherman with Channel 9 Pittsburgh.
我早该知道  太好了!
I should have known. That's great!
或许晚一点我们可以...
Maybe later we could...
什么都好
Whatever.
待在这里  答应我?
Stay right here. Promise me?
我马上回来  祝我好运
I'll be right back. Wish me luck.
祝你好运!
Good luck!
菲尔
Phil.
噢  丽塔
Oh, Rita.
谁是丽塔?
Who's Rita?
我怎么知道?
How should I know?
这算什么?  一夜情吗?
Is this some kind of one- night stand?
刚好相反  南茜  我爱你
On the contrary, Nancy. I love you.
我一直爱着你
I've always loved you.
这么说会很突兀  但是...
This is gonna seem sudden, but...
南茜  你愿意当我的老婆吗?
Nancy, will you be my wife?
丽塔
Rita.
是南茜
Nancy.
随便
Whatever.
一阵强风吹
A gust of wind.
狗开始叫
A dog barks.
卡车进来
Cue the truck.
拱石保全公司
赫曼走出来
Exit Herman.
走进银行
Walk into the bank.
菲力走出来  脸色不太好看
Exit Felix. Stand there with a not- so- bright look on your face.
桃莉出场
All right, Doris, come on.
调整一下胸罩  甜心  这样好多了
Fix your bra, honey. That's better.
"菲力"  "你好吗  桃莉?"
"Felix." "How you doing, Doris?"
"换一卷2毛5硬币好吗?"
"Can I have a roll of quarters?"
十  九  八...
Ten, nine, eight...
车子  六  五...
Car. Six, five...
硬币
Quarters.
三...
Three...
二...
two...
-怎样?  -我拿两袋还是一袋出来?
- What? - Did I bring out two bags or one?
不知道
I don't know.
海蒂第2集  周六日  日场
我以为要参加扮装派对
I thought we were going to a costume party.
就像我说的  我爱这部电影
It's like I said, I love this film.
我看过一百多遍了
I've seen it over a hundred times.
叫我布朗柯
I told you to call me Bronco.
对不起  布朗柯
Sorry, Bronco.
嗨  南茜
Hi, Nancy.
我以前的未婚妻  她们总是不记得我
My old fiance. They never remember me.
-一张全票和...  -两张全票
- That will be one adult and... - Two adults.
这只土拨鼠传说能预言早春的降临
the groundhog who, as legend has it, can predict the coming of an early spring.
今天我们要自问的问题是  "菲尔觉得运气如何?"
The question we have to ask ourselves today is, "Does Phil feel lucky?"
丽塔  如果你的生命只剩一天  你会怎么过?
Rita, if you only had one day to live, what would you do with it?
我不知道  菲尔  你要死了吗?
I don't know, Phil. What are you dying of?
我是说  假如地球快爆炸了  你怎么办?
I mean, the whole world is about to explode. What do you do?
我只想知道摄影机要放哪
I want to know where to put the camera.
你在找周末的约会对象吗?
Are you looking for a date for the weekend?
我对你有兴趣
I'm just interested in you.
你要什么?  你喜欢什么?  你在想什么?
What do you want? What do you like? What do you think about?
你对哪种男人有兴趣?
What kind of men are you interested in?
你做什么消遣?
What do you do for fun?
你是说真的还是想捉弄我?
Is this for real or are you trying to make me look like a fool?
我只想像一般人那样说话  他们不是这样说话的吗?
I'm just trying to talk like normal people talk. Isn't this how they talk?
-差不多  -那就跟我说话
- Close. - So talk to me.
我请你喝杯咖啡
Let me buy you a cup of coffee.
-加上一个甜甜圈  -好
- And a donut. - All right.
你想从生活中得到什么?
What do you want out of life?
我要每个人都想要的
I guess I want what everybody wants:
事业  爱情  婚姻  孩子
Career, love, marriage, children.
你现在有对象吗?
Are you seeing anyone?
这问题太隐私了
I think this is getting too personal.
我还不准备跟你分享这些
I don't think I'm ready to share this with you.
你呢?  你要什么?
How about you? What do you want?
我想要的是你这样的人
What I really want is someone like you.
-拜讬  -有什么不可以?
- Please. - Why not?
你在追寻什么?  你的理想对象要怎样?
What are you looking for? Who is your perfect guy?
首先  他会很谦虚  明白自己不够完美
First of all, he's too humble to know he's perfect.
我就是这样
That's me.
聪明  支持我  幽默
He's intelligent, supportive, funny.
聪明  支持你  幽默
Intelligent, supportive, funny.
我  我  我
Me, me, me.
-浪漫而且勇敢  -我也是
- He's romantic and courageous. - Me also.
他身材很好  但不会没事猛照镜子
He's got a good body, but doesn't look in the mirror every two minutes.
我身材很棒  有时几个月都不照镜子
I have a great body, and sometimes I go months without looking.
他善良  体贴又温柔
He's kind, sensitive and gentle.
不怕在我面前哭
He's not afraid to cry in front of me.
他是个男人吧?
This is a man, right?
他喜欢动物和小孩  还会换有大便的尿布
He likes animals and children, and he'll change poopy diapers.
一定要用"大便"这字眼吗?
Does he have to use the word "poopy"?
他会弹奏乐器  爱他的母亲
And he plays an instrument, and he loves his mother.
我真的和这个人很相近
I am really close on this one.
非常非常相近
Really really close.
他是菲尔·康纳
It's Phil Connors.
谢谢观赏
Hello. Thanks for watching.
今天离开的机率有多大?
So, what are the chances of getting out today?
车子还是发不动  赖瑞正在想办法
The van still won't start. Larry's working on it.
谁知道会怎样  请你喝杯酒好吗?
Wouldn't you know it. Can I buy you a drink?
金宾威士忌  加冰块  加水
Jim Beam, ice, water.
你呢  小姐?
For you, miss?
甜苦艾酒加冰块  放柠檬片
Sweet vermouth on the rocks with a twist, please.
今天出城的机率有多大?
What are the chances of getting out of town today?
车子还是发不动  赖瑞正在想办法
The van still won't start. Larry's working on it.
谁知道会怎样  请你喝杯酒好吗?
Wouldn't you know it. Can I buy you a drink?
甜苦艾酒加冰块  放柠檬片
Sweet vermouth, rocks with a twist, please.
-你呢  小姐?  -一样
- For you, miss? - The same.
-那是我最爱喝的酒  -我也是
- That's my favorite drink. - Mine too.
它总会让我想到罗马阳光洒在建筑物上的样子
It always makes me think of Rome, the way the sun hits the buildings.
我们要敬什么?
What shall we drink to?
敬土拨鼠
To the groundhog.
我都敬世界和平
I always drink to world peace.
请你喝杯酒好吗?
Can I buy you a drink?
甜苦艾酒加冰块  放柠檬片
Sweet vermouth, rocks with a twist, please.
你呢  小姐?
For you, miss?
一样  那是我最爱的酒
The same. That's my favorite drink.
我也是
Mine too.
它总会让我想到罗马...
It always makes me think of Rome...
阳光洒在建筑物上的样子
the way the sun hits the buildings.
我们要敬什么?
What shall we drink to?
我想祈祷世界和平
I like to say a prayer and drink to world peace.
敬世界和平
To world peace.
阿门
Amen.
-很好吃  -我不是说过了吗?
- This is wonderful. - Didn't I tell you?
你怎么这么了解普苏塔尼?
How do you know so much about Punxsutawney?
我常待在这里
I've spent a lot of time here.
-小镇居民实在多了  -那也是我的感觉
- Small town people are more real. - That's how I feel.
真的?  想吃白巧克力吗?
Really? Would you like some white chocolate?
-别让我恶心了  -不吃白巧克力
- Don't make me sick. - No white chocolate.
这感觉好熟悉
There is something familiar about this.
-你有似曾相识的感觉吗?  -你不是刚问过吗?
- Do you ever have deja vu? - Didn't you just ask me that?
人们太重视事业了
People place too much emphasis on their careers.
我希望人们能住在高山上
I wish we could all live in the mountains at high altitude.
我希望五年后能办到
That's where I see myself in five years.
-你呢?  -我同意
- How about you? - I agree.
我喜欢顺其自然  看会怎样
I like to go with the flow, see where it leads me.
结果现在你变成这样
It's led you here.
我没有学以致用
It's a million miles from where I started in college.
你不是念新闻或传播的吗?
You weren't in broadcasting or journalism?
信不信由你  我主修十九世纪法国诗
Believe it or not, I studied 19th- century French poetry.
真是浪费时间
What a waste of time.
对别人来说那非常浪费时间
For someone else that would be an incredible waste of time.
你选择那领域真有勇气  难以置信
It was so bold of you to choose that. It's incredible.
你一定是意志很坚强的人
You must be a very strong person.
人们太重视事业了
People place too much emphasis on their careers.
我希望人们能住在高山上
I wish we could all live in the mountains, at high altitudes.
我希望五年后能办到
That's where I see myself in five years.
-你呢?  -我同意
- How about you? - I agree.
我喜欢顺其自然  看会怎样
I like to go with the flow, see what happens.
结果你变成现在这样
It's gotten you here.
我没有学以致用
It's a million miles from where I started in college.
你不是念新闻或传播的吗?
You weren't in broadcasting or journalism?
信不信由你  我主修十九世纪法国诗
Believe it or not, I studied 19th- century French poetry.
你会说法语
You speak French.
是的
Oui.
-我长大后就没玩过这个  -我也一样
- I haven't done this since I was a kid. - Me neither.
-很好玩  -干净又好玩
- It's fun. - It's good, clean fun.
希望有天能和我的孩子一起玩
I hope that one day I can do this with my own children.
哪里弄来的?
Where did you get that?
我到一家雪人商店
I went over to the snowman shop.
刺客!
An assassin!
我会保护你  陛下
I'll protect you, Your Majesty.
我愿为你而死  你们不会得逞的
I shall die for you! You shall not take her!
寻找掩护  小姐
Find cover, my lady!
-臂力不错  -我来丢一些大的雪球
- Nice arm. - I'm getting some good ones.
那边有一个  丢得不错
There's a boy. That's a boy. Good try.
-丢中了  -拉我一把
- Got him. - Help me.
-怎样?  -我好惊讶  我不常这样的
- What? - I'm amazed, and I'm not easily amazed.
-什么事?  -一天开始时的期望...
- About what? - How you can start a day...
和最后的结果居然完全不同
with one kind of expectation and end up so completely different.
你喜欢今天的结果吗?
Do you like the way this day is turning out?
非常喜欢
I like it very much.
今天很完美  这是人计划不出来的
It's a perfect day. You couldn't plan a day like this.
可以  只是会很花功夫
You can. It just takes an awful lot of work.
进来  给你看样东西
Come on in. I want to show you something.
-不太好吧  -我想也是
- I don't think I should. - I don't think you should either.
所以看样东西你就得走  一下子就好
That's why I'll show you one thing and kick you out. Just one minute.
好温馨
It's just lovely.
想坐着看假炉火吗?
Would you like to sit and stare at the fake fire?
这房间真棒
It's really a wonderful room.
到现在才棒
It is now.
我不知道  我们不该这么做
I don't know. I don't think we should do this.
我想也是
I don't either.
我考虑之后  我们还是该做
On second thought, I think we should.
这是完美一天的完美句点
It's the perfect end to a perfect day.
我觉得太快了
It's a little fast for me.
我也是
Me too.
也许我该走了
Maybe I should go.
你要去哪里?
Where would you go?
为什么?  我们有完美的炉火
Why? We've got a perfect fire.
我这里有一首法国诗  是波德莱尔写的
I've got some French poetry here. Baudelaire.
我唸给你听
I will read to you.
我的窗台上有冰淇淋
I've got ice cream on the windowsill.
等一下
Hold on a minute.
-香草脆果巧克力?  -我爱死这个了
- Rocky Road? - I love Rocky Road.
我想也是
I thought so.
你得留下来
You have to stay.
我累了  我们明天再见面
I'm tired. We can see each other tomorrow.
今晚  一定要是今晚
Tonight. It's gotta be tonight.
-真的  -待一会儿吧
- Really. - Just stay for awhile.
你乐意的话  多待一会儿
If you like it, stay for a while longer and awhile longer.
-别搞砸了  -我也不想
- Let's not spoil it. - I don't want to spoil it either.
你明白我不能留下来陪你
You know I can't stay with you.
为什么?  我爱你
Why not? I love you.
你爱我?
You love me?
-你根本还不了解我  -我了解你
- You don't even know me. - I know you.
我不敢相信自己会信以为真
I can't believe I fell for this.
这一整天都是陷阱
This whole day has just been one long setup.
-不是  -我痛恨谎言
- It hasn't. - And I hate fudge.
没有白巧克力  没有谎言
No white chocolate. No fudge.
你在做什么?  你在列什么单子吗?
What are you doing? Are you making some kind of list?
你有打电话问我朋友我喜欢和不喜欢什么吗?
Did you call my friends and ask what I like and what I don't like?
-这就是你所谓的爱吗?  -这是真的  这是爱
- Is this what love is for you? - This is real. This is love.
别说了!  你一定是疯了
Stop saying that! You must be crazy.
我绝不会爱上你这种人  你只爱你自己
I could never love someone like you. You only love yourself.
不对  我甚至不喜欢自己  再给我一次机会
That's not true. I don't even like myself. Give me another chance.
你这个感情骗子!
That's for making me care about you.
-我长大后就没再玩过  -我也一样
- I haven't done this since I was a kid. - Me neither.
-很好玩  -干净又好玩
- It's fun. - Good, clean fun too.
今天世界缺乏的就是这个
That's what's missing in the world today.
我等不及和自己的孩子一起玩
I can't wait to do this with my own children.
天啊  我想要很多孩子!
Golly, I want lots of kids!
我要领养孩子  还要自己生
I want to adopt. I want to have my own.
我要收养小孩  我在雪人城找到的
I want foster kids. I got this at Snowman City.
有个小孩对我们丢雪球!
Some kid threw a snowball at us!
过来!  我们好好玩玩!
Come here! Let's have some fun!
真希望他们是我的孩子!
I wish these were my own kids!
你们有人打算被领养吗?
Are any of you up for adoption?
这里有个很棒的对象!  很好玩吧?
Here's a humdinger over here! Wasn't that great?
住手!
Stop it!
在这边!
Over here!
你到哪去了?  你错过好玩的东西了
Where have you been? You're missing all the fun.
你的样子好糟糕
You look terrible.
怎么了?  睡不好吗?
What happened? Rough night?
快起床
Okay, campers, rise and shine.
别忘了装备  今天外面很冷
Don't forget your booties because it's cold out there today.
外面每天都很冷
It's cold out there every day.
哪个国家最大的湖恰帕拉湖位于瓜达拉哈拉附近?
This country's largest lake, Chapala, is located near the city...
答案是墨西哥
- of Guadalajara. - What is Mexico?
-答对了  -"湖泊与河流"  四百元
- Correct. - "Lakes and Rivers," 400.
纽约州中西部哪个湖群最大的湖是塞尼加湖?
Seneca is the largest of these lakes in West- Central New York.
-手指湖吗?  -答对了
- What are the Finger Lakes? - Correct.
湖泊与河流  六百元
"Lakes and Rivers" for 600.
哪个南美洲的湖流入波利维亚更小的湖?
This South American lake drains into the smaller lake in Bolivia.
-的的喀喀湖  -答对了
- What is Titicaca? - Correct.
-"湖泊与河流"  一千元  -因为源自冰河...
- "Lakes and Rivers" for 1,000. - Milky colored...
答案是隆河
What is the Rhone?
这条河的河水则已清澈
When entering Lake Geneva, this river is clear upon exiting.
吉姆?  隆河  你获得一千元
Jim? The Rhone is good for $ 1,000.
-离领先还有五百元  -我选发明家  两百元
- You are $500 off the lead. - Let's go to "Inventors" for 200.
真令人同情
This is pitiful.
一千个人冻得要命  等着要崇拜一只老鼠
A thousand people freezing their butts off, waiting to worship a rat.
真是天大的骗局  土拨鼠节以前是别有意义的
What a hype. Groundhog Day used to mean something in this town.
他们以前把鼠拖出来吃掉!
They used to pull the hog out and eat it!
你们全都是伪君子!
You're hypocrites, all of you!
你对我说的话有意见吗?
You got a problem with what I'm saying?
嘴巴张开  过来说啊
Untie your tongue, and you come out here and talk.
我惹你不高兴吗  公主?
Am I upsetting you, Princess?
你们想问天气  却问到错的菲尔
You want a prediction about the weather, you're asking the wrong Phil.
我帮你们预测
I'll give you a winter prediction.
天气会很冷...
It's gonna be cold...
天色会很阴暗...
it's gonna be gray...
你们一辈子都会那样
and it's gonna last you for the rest of your life.
每年这时候  全国目光都转移到...
Once again, the eyes of the nation have turned here to this...
这个宾州西部的小镇上
tiny village in western Pennsylvania.
只要这只土拨鼠一直看到自己的影子...
There is no way that this winter...
今年冬天...
is ever going to end...
就不会结束
as long as this groundhog keeps seeing his shadow.
我没办法了
I don't see any other way out.
要有人阻止它
He has to be stopped.
我得阻止它
I have to stop him.
很好  菲尔
Real good, Phil.
他疯了
He's crazy.
我好担心  菲尔真的出了问题
I'm worried. I think there's something really wrong with Phil.
菲尔真的很不对劲
There's a lot of things really wrong with Phil.
我已经快完蛋了
I've come to the end of me.
没有出路了
There's no way out now.
我要你记得我们曾共度美好的一天
I just want you to remember we had a beautiful day together once.
好了  小家伙  干得好
All right, little fella. Good job.
-它对我笑  看到没?  -我相信它有
- He smiled at me. Did you see that? - I believe he did.
小家伙  进去吧
Okay, little fella. There you go.
先生  有什么事吗?
Hi, mister. Something I can do you for?
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
杰克  快通知大家!  有人绑架菲尔!
Jake, get the word out! Somebody kidnapped Phil!
我们去追他!
We're going after him!
怎么会有人要偷土拨鼠?
Why would anybody steal a groundhog?
我想到几个可能原因  性变态
I can probably think of a couple of reasons. Pervert.
-他一定抓狂了  -这下可精彩了
- He must have just snapped! - This should be good.
他在干嘛?  他在想什么?
What is he doing? What can he be thinking?
对四只脚的动物来说算不错了
That's not bad for a quadruped.
要看照后镜
You gotta check your mirrors, just the side of your eye.
对
That's it.
他们在追我们!  开快点!
They're chasing us! Come on, make it fun!
开车别激动
Don't drive angry.
这里没别的出路  逮到他了!
Hot dog! There's no way out except the way we came in. We got him now!
-他在干嘛?  -不知道
- What is he doing? - I don't know.
要开枪的话  瞄高一点  别打到土拨鼠
If you gotta shoot, aim high. I don't wanna hit the groundhog.
不能让观众等太久
We mustn't keep our public waiting.
好戏上场了
It's show time.
好  赖瑞  倒数三秒...
All right, on me, Larry, in three!
二  一
Two, one.
他说不定没事
He might be okay.
这下大概出事了
Probably not now.
混蛋
Nuts.
睡得好吗  康纳先生?
Did you sleep well, Mr. Connors?
想吃土司吗?
Would you like some toast?
-怎么回事?  -天啊
- What's going on? - My God.
是他
That's him.
他真的是个好人
He was a really great guy.
我真的很喜欢他
I really liked him a lot.
什么  你说什么?
I'm sorry. What was that again?
-我是神!  -你是神?
- I'm a god! - You're a god?
我是神  不过应该不是上帝
I'm a god. I'm not the God, I don't think.
只因为你车祸没死?
Because you survived a car wreck?
要点餐了吗?
You ready to order?
我不光是车祸没死  或只是昨天被炸死
I didn't just survive a wreck. I wasn't just blown up yesterday.
我被刺杀  枪杀  毒害...
I have been stabbed, shot, poisoned...
冻死  吊死  电击
frozen, hung, electrocuted...
-还被火烧  -真的?
- and burned. - Really?
每天早上醒来却毫发无伤
Every morning I wake up fine, not a dent in the fender.
-我不会死  -今日特餐是蓝莓松饼
- I am an immortal. - Special today is blueberry waffles.
你说这些干嘛?
Why are you telling me this?
因为我要你相信我
Because I want you to believe in me.
你不是神  相信我  我上过12年天主教学校
You're not a god. You can take my word for. This is 12 years of Catholic school talking.
我可以等一下再来帮你点
I could come back if you're not ready.
你怎么知道我不是神?
How do you know I'm not a god?
拜讬!
Please!
-你怎么知道?  -因为不可能!
- How do you know? - Because it's not possible!
-我等一下再来  -桃莉
- I'll come back. - Doris!
这是桃莉  她姐夫卡尔是老板
This is Doris. Her brother- in- law, Carl, owns this diner.
她从17岁就在这里上班  她希望死前能到巴黎一游
She's worked here since she was 17. She wants to see Paris before she dies.
-天啊  我好想去  -你在干嘛?
- Boy, would I! - What are you doing?
-黛比和她的未婚夫佛瑞  -我认识你们吗?
- Debbie Kleiser and her fiance, Fred. - Do I know you?
他们本来今天下午要结婚  但是黛比要重新考虑
They're supposed to be married this afternoon, but Debbie is reconsidering.
-什么?  -好美的戒指
- What? - Lovely ring.
这是比尔  他当服务生三年了
This is Bill who's been a waiter for three years...
因为他大学不念了  需要工作
since he left Penn State and had to get work.
他喜欢这里  会画玩具兵  还是同性恋
He likes the town, paints toy soldiers, and he's gay.
没错
I am.
这是贾斯  他讨厌这里的生活  希望能留在海军服役
This is Gus. He hates his life here and wishes he'd stayed in the Navy.
20年后我退伍还能领半薪
I could have retired on half pay after 20 years.
这是什么诡计吗?
Is this some kind of trick?
也许上帝会耍诡计  也许他不是万能的
Maybe the real God uses tricks. Maybe He's not omnipotent.
他只是在我们身边很久了  所以什么都知道
He's just been around so long, He knows everything.
-那是谁?  -这是汤姆
- Who's that? - This is Tom.
他是矿工  一直做到矿坑关闭
He worked in the coal mine till they closed it down.
-她呢?  -爱莉丝
- Her? - Alice.
婴儿时从爱尔兰过来  一辈子都住在艾里
She came from Ireland as a baby and lived in Erie most of her life.
-他说的对  -南茜
- He's right. - Nancy.
她在服装店上班  兴奋时会发出花栗鼠的声音
She works in the dress shop and makes chipmunk noises when she gets excited.
-是真的  -你怎么会认识这些人?
- It's true. - How do you know these people?
我什么都知道  5秒钟后  有个服务生会打破盘子
I know everything. In five seconds, a waiter will drop a tray of dishes.
-五  四  三  二  一  -太疯狂了
- Five, four, three, two, one. - This is nuts.
够了
That's enough.
-你也了解我吗?  -我了解你的一切
- Do you know me too? - I know all about you.
你喜欢制作节目  却不希望光待在第9频道
You like producing, but you're hoping for more than Channel 9 Pittsburgh.
这大家都知道
Everyone knows that.
你喜欢船  却不喜欢海
You like boats, but not the ocean.
夏天你会跟家人到山上的一座湖
You go to a mountain lake in the summer with your family.
那里有长长的木船渠  还有一间船库...
There's a long, wooden dock and a boathouse...
屋顶的木板都不见了...
with boards missing from the roof...
还有一个你会爬下去独处的地方
and a place you used to crawl underneath to be alone.
你喜欢法文诗和莱因石
You're a sucker for French poetry and rhinestones.
你很大方
You're very generous.
你对陌生人和小孩都很和善
You're kind to strangers and children.
当你站在雪地里  你看起来就像个天使
And when you stand in the snow, you look like an angel.
你怎么办到的?
How are you doing this?
我说了我每天在普苏塔尼醒来...
I wake up every day right here...
每天都是2月2日
in Punxsutawney, and it's always February 2.
我没办法改变这情况
There's nothing I can do about it.
如果你还怀疑的话...
If you still doubt me...
10秒钟之后...
in ten seconds...
赖瑞会进来带你走...
Larry will come through that door and take you away from me...
但你不能让他带你走
but you can't let him.
请相信我  一定要相信我
Please believe me. You've got to believe me.
好了没?  趁天气变坏前赶快走
You ready? We better get going if we're going to stay ahead of the weather.
那是什么?
What's that?
趁天气变坏前赶快走
We better get going if we're going to stay ahead of the weather.
也许真的发生了
Maybe it really is happening.
不然你怎么知道那么多?
How else could you know so much?
不可能  我没那么聪明
There is no way. I'm not that smart.
也许今天我该跟你在一起...
Maybe I should spend the day with you...
当客观目击者  看发生什么事
as an objective witness, just to see what happens.
听起来好像科学实验
This sounds like a science project.
专心一点  丢进去
Concentrate. You gotta want it.
重点在手腕  不在手指...
It's more in the wrist than the finger. It's just gotta...
丢进帽子里  丢!
Be the hat! Come on! Go!
我要花一年才能学会
It would take me a year to get good at this.
6个月  每天4到5小时  你就能变成专家
Six months. Four to five hours a day, and you'd be an expert.
你这样打发永恒的时间吗?
Is this what you do with eternity?
现在你知道了
Now you know.
这还不是最糟的
That's not the worst part.
最糟的是什么?
What's the worst part?
最糟的是明天你会忘掉这一切...
The worst part is that tomorrow you will have forgotten all about this...
又会把我当混蛋
and you'll treat me like a jerk again.
-没关系  我是混蛋  -你不是
- It's all right. I am a jerk. - You're not.
没什么差别
It doesn't make any difference.
我已经自杀很多次了  我早就不存在了
I've killed myself so many times, I don't even exist anymore.
有时我倒希望我有上千辈子
Sometimes I wish I had a thousand lifetimes.
我不知道  菲尔  或许这不是诅咒
I don't know, Phil. Maybe it's not a curse.
端看你如何看待它
It just depends on how you look at it.
天啊  你真是个乐观的女人!
Gosh, you're an upbeat lady!
-我觉得今天很愉快  -我也是
- It's been a really nice day for me. - Me too.
如果不算太无聊的话  改天我们可以再来一次
Maybe, if it's not too boring, we could do it again sometime.
希望如此
I hope so.
你还在
You're still here.
我以为你会消失或我会消失!
I thought you were supposed to disappear or I was or something!
要等到6点
Not until 6:00.
你这小人!
You rat!
我没说过在午夜
I never said midnight.
-你知道我在等午夜!  -你要走了吗?
- You knew I was waiting for midnight! - Does this mean you're gonna leave?
没有啊
No.
好
Good.
对不起
I'm sorry.
没关系  你可以睡
It's all right. You can fall asleep.
我保证不碰你...  太多
I promise I won't touch you, much.
没关系  我不累
That's all right. I'm not tired.
你刚刚说什么?
What were you saying?
你听到最后一句话是...
I think the last thing that you heard was...
"只有上帝能造树"
"Only God can make a tree."
真的?
Really?
我想说的是...
What I wanted to say was...
你是我一生中见过  最善良  体贴...
I think you're the kindest, sweetest, prettiest person...
最美丽的人
I've ever met in my life.
我没见过...
I've never seen anyone...
比你待人更好的人
that's nicer to people than you are.
第一次见到你...
The first time I saw you...
我就有种奇妙的感觉
something happened to me.
我没告诉过你  但...
I never told you, but...
我知道我要紧紧地拥抱你
I knew that I wanted to hold you as hard as I could.
我配不上你
I don't deserve someone like you.
但如果可以...
But if I ever could...
我发誓我会爱你...
I swear I would love you...
一生一世
for the rest of my life.
你刚才说什么?
Did you say something?
晚安
Good night.
谁要咖啡?  趁热喝
Who wants coffee? Get it while it's hot.
谢了  菲尔
Thanks, Phil.
-赖瑞?  脱脂牛奶  两匙糖  -谢了  菲尔
- Larry? Skim milk, two sugars. - Thanks, Phil.
-点心?  -我们在架机器
- Pastry? - We're just setting up.
自己挑
Take your pick.
谢谢  覆盆子  好棒
Thanks. Raspberry. Great.
我刚跟巴斯特谈过  他是活动主办人
I was just talking with Buster Green, the head groundhog honcho.
他说机器架在那边会拍到比较好的镜头
He said if we set up over here, we might get a better shot.
-你觉得如何?  -好像不错
- What do you think? - Sounds good.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
我们过去吧
Let's go for it.
-干得好  -我们运气好
- Good work. - Maybe we'll get lucky.
我帮你搬器材
Let me help you with the heavy stuff.
你喝你的咖啡  我来
You got your coffee. I'll get it.
我们没聊过天  你有孩子吗?
We never talk. Do you have kids?
我想上钢琴课
I'd like a piano lesson, please.
我现在有学生  如果你明天来  我可以帮你安排看看
I'm with a student now. If you come back tomorrow, I can squeeze you in.
我想马上开始  我可以给你一千元
I kind of want to get started. I could give you $1,000.
进来
Come on in.
早安!  要去看土拨鼠吗?
Good morning! Off to see the groundhog?
你想今年会是早春吗?
You think it will be an early spring?
"冬天在户外沉睡"
"Winter slumbering in the open air...
"展开笑颜"
wears on his smiling face...
"春天的梦"
a dream of spring."
再见
Au revoir.
-菲尔  -嗨  丽塔  赖瑞
- Phil? - Hi, Rita, Lerry.
雕得怎么样?
How's she look?
-很漂亮  -谢谢
- Great. - Thank you.
你知道他会冰雕吗?
Did you know he could ice sculpt?
不
No.
不错  你说这是你第一次上课?
Not bad. You say this is your first lesson?
我爸当过钢琴搬运工
My father was a piano mover.
我就知道是你
I thought it was you.
尼德·莱尔森
Ned Ryerson.
我好想你
I have missed you so much.
我不知道你要去哪  但你能请病假吗?
I don't know where you're headed, but can you call in sick?
我得走了
I gotta get going.
见到你真好
It's good to see you.
老爹
Hello, father.
我们找个暖和的地方
Let's get you someplace warm.
记得我吗?
Remember me?
抱歉  先生  是你带那位老先生进来的吗?
Excuse me, sir. Are you the one who brought the old man in?
他怎么样?
How is he?
他刚过世了
He just passed away.
死因是什么?
What did he die of?
年纪大  时候到了
He was just old. It was just his time.
-我要看他的病历  对不起  -先生!
- I want to see his chart. Excuse me. - Sir!
你不能进去
You can't come in here.
这是管制区
This is a restricted area.
病历呢?
Where's the chart?
人总会死的
Sometimes people just die.
今天不行
Not today.
碗底的不好舀
It's hard down there at the bottom.
-来了  -谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
起来啊  老爹!
Come on, Dad! Come on, Pop!
呼吸啊  老爹!
Breathe, Pop!
当契诃夫看到漫长的冬天...
When Chekhov saw the long winter...
他看刺骨黑暗的冬天还有希望逝去
he saw a winter bleak and dark and bereft of hope.
然而我们知道冬天只是生命周期的另一步
Yet we know that winter is just another step in the cycle of life.
站在普苏塔尼人之间...
But standing here among the people of Punxsutawney...
靠他们的壁炉和热情取暖...
and basking in the warmth of their hearths and hearts...
漫长而光亮的冬天...
I couldn't imagine a better fate...
也成了最好的时光
than a long and lustrous winter.
我是菲尔·康纳  在普苏塔尼报导
From Punxsutawney, it's Phil Connors.
再会
So long.
说得非常好  菲尔
Very nice speech, Phil.
-谢谢  -谢了
- Thank you. - Thanks.
-你们两个觉得怎样?  -我被你感动了
- How was that for you two? - Man, you touched me.
-谢了  赖瑞  -谢谢
- Thanks, Larry. - Thank you.
我得走了
I gotta go.
真令人惊喜  没想到你这么有才华
That was surprising. I didn't know you were so versatile.
有时我自己也很惊讶
I surprise myself sometimes.
想喝点咖啡吗?
Would you like to get some coffee?
我很想  改天好吗?  我有事要做
I'd love to. Can I have a rain check? I've got some errands to run.
什么事?  我以为我们要回去了
What errands? I thought we were going back.
抓好  小子
Hold it, fella!
你该说什么?
What do you say?
兔崽子  你从没谢过我!
You little brat. You have never thanked me!
也许明天见吧!
I'll see you tomorrow, maybe!
-怎么了?  -全被你毁了
- Now what? - You've totaled it.
只是爆胎而已  别紧张!
It's only a flat tire. Now just be patient. Just cool it!
-是地震!  -不是地震!
- It's an earthquake! - It's not an earthquake!
怎么回事?
What is it?
谢谢你  年轻人
Thank you, young man.
没什么  我有轮胎和千斤顶
It's nothing. I had the tire and the jack.
坐好  马上好
Just be comfortable. Be a minute.
他是谁?
Who is that?
一定是修车厂的
Must be from the motor club.
-天啊  他心脏病发作了!  -怎么办?
- My God! He's having a heart attack! - What should I do?
-叫救护车  律师  医生!  -妈  他没有呼吸了!
- Call an ambulance, a lawyer, a doctor! - Mom, I don't think he's breathing!
没事了
I think that did it.
想吃牛排就得装锐利一点的牙
If you're gonna eat steak, get some sharper teeth.
-请慢用  -谢谢
- Enjoy your lunch. - Thank you.
他是谁?  我没事了
Who was that? I'm fine.
-真的吗?  -对  吃吧
- Are you sure? - Oh, yes. Eat.
人们不懂其中奥妙
People just don't understand what is involved in this.
这是一种艺术形式
This is an art form.
大部分的人会以为...
You know, I think most people just think that...
我拿摄影机对着东西拍
I hold the camera and point it at stuff.
其实不光是那样
There is a lot more to it than just that.
有兴趣看车上的东西吗?
Would you be at all interested in seeing the inside of the van?
我真的要回派对去了
You know, I really have to get back to the party.
好主意  我跟你去  我留一点小费
Great idea. I'll go with you. Let me just drop a tip here.
你好吗?  丽塔  这是南茜
How are you? Rita, this is Nancy.
我们要去参加派对
We were just going to the party.
-你要去吗?  -好像很好玩
- You going? - Sounds like fun.
我们应该通知菲尔
Maybe we should call Phil.
我想他已经在那里了
I think he's already in there.
-他很棒吧?  -棒呆了!
- Isn't he good? - He's great!
他是我的学生
He's my student.
我好骄傲
I'm so proud.
谢谢
Thank you.
欢迎光临我们的派对
Welcome to our party.
-我不知道你弹得那么好  -我多才多艺
- I didn't know you could play like that. - I'm versatile.
修车厂的年轻人  你真好心
It's that nice, young man from the motor club.
-再次谢谢你  -没什么  女士
- Thank you again. - It's nothing, ladies.
他是杰佛逊郡  动作最快的修车工
He's the fastest jack in Jefferson County.
那是怎么回事?
What was that all about?
我真的不知道  她们整晚一直吃我豆腐
I really don't know. They've been hitting on me all night.
你在这里
There you are.
我还没好好谢谢你救巴斯特
I never thanked you properly for what you did for Buster.
他本来一定会噎死的
He would have choked for sure.
可能会  他想吞下一整条牛
He may have. He was trying to swallow a whole cow.
-我欠你一次  老兄  -好好把握  他是难得的好人
- I owe you one, buddy. - Hang onto him, dear. He's a real find.
-你今天做了什么事?  -和平常一样
- What did you do today? - Same old, same old.
对不起
Excuse me.
佛瑞  婚礼还好吗?
Fred, how was the wedding?
我要谢谢你让黛比想通了
I just wanted to thank you for making Debbie go through with it.
我只是激发她对你的热情
All I did was fan the flame of her passion for you.
你最棒了
You are the best.
不  你才棒
No, you are the best.
丽塔  这是黛比和佛瑞
Rita, this is Debbie and Fred Kleiser.
-拿去  恭喜你们  -这是什么?
- Here you go, kids. Congratulations. - What is this?
不会吧!
No way!
疯狂摔角!
Wrestlemania!
你怎么知道?  反正我们都要去匹兹堡!
How did you know? We're gonna be in Pittsburgh anyway!
-谢谢  你真够朋友!  -这才是最棒的!
- Thank you! You're a real pal! - This is the best!
-我不懂  -我想也是
- I don't understand. - I guess not.
大家怎么都认识你?  你一年才来一次
How does everyone know you? You only come here once a year.
你好像是城里最受欢迎的人
You seem like the most popular person in town.
对不起  康纳医生吗?
Excuse me. Dr. Connors?
我要谢谢你治好菲力的背
I want to thank you for fixing Felix's back.
他又能整理住家周围了
He can even help around the house again.
真遗憾  菲力
I'm sorry to hear that, Felix.
"康纳医生"?
"Dr. Connors"?
那是一种荣誉头衔
It's kind of an honorary title.
-怎么回事?  -我真的不知道
- What is going on? - I really don't know.
你一定在搞什么鬼
There is something going on with you.
你想听完整版还是浓缩版?
Would you like the long version or the short one?
先从浓缩版开始
Let's start with the short and go from there.
好  各位注意
Okay, folks. Attention.
拍卖单身汉时间到了  你们都知道规则
Time for the big bachelor auction. You all know the rules.
有资格的单身汉到前面来...
All the eligible bachelors come down in front...
女士们请出价!
and you ladies bid on them!
你们可以和他们做任何事  不准问问题!
You get to do whatever you want with them. No questions asked!
只要合法  我不想知道你们做什么事!
I don't want to know about it, as long as it's legal!
钱包拿出来  请记得这是慈善活动!
Get out your pocketbooks and remember, it's all for charity!
你在这里干嘛?  上台去啊
What are you doing down here? Go on. Get up there.
我有十块钱  你是我的了!
I got ten bucks that says you're mine!
-我找到第一个受害者  -上来吧!
- Buster, I got your first victim. - Come up here!
好!  这位优良男士该出价多少?
All right! What am I bid for this fine specimen?
5块钱!
Five dollars!
从5元起跳
The bidding has begun at five dollars.
-10元!  -15元!
- Ten dollars! - Fifteen!
-20元!  -25元!
- Twenty! - Twenty- five!
-30!  -35!
- Thirty! - Thirty- five!
-40!  -45!
- Forty! - Forty- five!
-50!  -55!
- Fifty! - Fifty- five!
-60!  -有人出到60了  还有更高的吗?
- Sixty! - I'm bid sixty. Do I hear more?
339元8毛8!
Three hundred and thirty- nine dollars and eighty- eight cents!
我们不接受出价了  就卖给...
We can't accept any more bids. That's sold...
出339元8毛8的女士!
to the little lady for $339.88!
恭喜
Congratulations.
单身汉们!  下一个是谁?
Okay, bachelors! Who's next?
好!  各位出价多少?
All right! What am I bid for this guy?
有人出1块半吗?
Do I hear a buck and a half?
有没有?
Anybody?
-7毛5?  -我出2毛5!
- Seventy- five cents? - I bid two bits!
出2毛5的女士得标!
Sold to the lady for twenty- five cents!
我得标了!
I got him!
菲尔·康纳!  我就知道是你!
Phil Connors! I thought that was you!
这是尼德·莱尔森  我新的保险经纪人
This is Ned Ryerson, my new insurance agent.
是啊!
I'll say!
我有20年没见到这家伙了
I have not seen this guy for 20 years.
他跟我买了所有的保险  终身险  单一险...
He comes to me and buys whole life, term, uniflex...
火险  窃盗险  汽车险  牙齿险  健康险...
fire, theft, auto, dental, health...
加上意外死亡  解雇险和水灾险
with the optional death and dismemberment plan, water damage.
今天是我这辈子最棒的一天
This is the best day of my life.
我也是
Mine too.
-我们要去哪?  -别搞砸了
- Where are we going? - Let's not spoil it.
我懂了!
I got that!
-我为什么不能看?  -因为你会让我分心
- Why can't I look? - Because you bother me a lot.
我很冷  还要坐多久?
I'm getting cold. How much longer do I have to sit here?
我要让你值回票价  你出最高价得标
I'm just giving you your money's worth. You paid top dollar for me.
我认为你是物超所值
I think you were a bargain.
你这么说真好  也许你说对了
Sweet of you to say. You're probably right.
-完成了没?  -快好了
- Is it finished yet? - Almost.
我还要淋上樱桃糖浆才能吃
I still have to put cherry syrup on top and then we can eat it.
快点!  我快冻死了!
Come on! I'm freezing!
等一下  好了  我把它转向灯光
One second. All right. Let me turn toward the light.
不可思议
It's amazing.
好漂亮
It's beautiful.
-你怎么做到的?  -你的脸我非常熟悉...
- How did you do that? - I know your face so well...
我能闭着眼睛做
I could have done it with my eyes closed.
好漂亮  我不知道该说什么
It's lovely. I don't know what to say.
我知道
I do.
无论明天发生什么事...
No matter what happens tomorrow...
或者往后的生命中发生什么事...
or for the rest of my life...
我现在都很快乐  因为我爱你
I'm happy now because I love you.
我也很快乐
I think I'm happy too.
-拜讬  别又来了  -那首歌很棒!
- Please, not again. - That is a great song!
-才怪!  -别听这家伙的...
- It's not! - Don't listen to this man...
太早了
It's too early.
有点不一样
Something is different.
好事还是坏事?
Good or bad?
只要不一样就是好事...
Anything different is good...
不过这真的很好
but this could be real good.
你怎么在这里?
Why are you here?
我买了你  你是我的
I bought you. I own you.
你怎么还在这里?
But why are you still here?
你叫我留下  我就留下来
You said stay, so I stayed.
我叫你留下你就留下?
I said stay, so you stayed?
连牧羊犬都不听我的话
I can't even make a collie stay.
我去看样东西
I gotta check something.
留下来
Stay.
他们不见了!
They're gone!
他们全都不见了!
They're all gone!
-知道今天是什么吗?  -什么?
- Do you know what today is? - What?
今天就是明天
Today is tomorrow.
发生了
It happened.
-你在这里  -我在这里
- You're here. - I'm here.
你昨晚怎么不像这样子?  你睡着了
Why weren't you like this last night? You just fell sleep.
昨晚是漫长一天的结束
It was the end of a very long day.
今天我能帮你做什么事吗?
Is there anything I can do for you today?
我一定会想出事情给你做
I'm sure I can think of something.
好漂亮!
It's so beautiful!
我们住在这里吧
Let's live here.
先租一间房子再说
We'll rent to start.